<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="_mainpage" xml:lang="en-US">
<title>HarvesterHarvester</title>
<indexterm><primary>HarvesterHarvester</primary></indexterm>

<para><anchor xml:id="_index_1md_README"/>A tool for harvesting data out of <link xlink:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harvester_(video_game)"><emphasis>Harvester</emphasis>&apos;s (DigiFX Interactive, 1996)</link> dat files.</para>

<para>This program is the first piece of a toolchain that I&apos;m developing as I work to reverse engineering <emphasis>Harvester</emphasis>. The ultimate goal of this project is to eventually port the game to a more modern graphics framework (Raylib or OpenGL) just for fun/to teach myself the basics of reverse engineering.</para>

<para>The program works in two steps:<orderedlist>
<listitem>
<para>It reconstructs the original disk images that Harvester would&apos;ve shipped with in 1996<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><emphasis>Note</emphasis>: if you own the original game disks, this step is not needed.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>See USAGE.md for more details.</para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para>It extracts the dat files contained within those new directories in order to give you full access to all of the game&apos;s files.</para>
</listitem></orderedlist>
</para>
<section xml:id="_index_1autotoc_md1">
<title>Future Projects</title>
<para>The next step for me in this project will be creating an asset viewer.</para>

<para>This will require me to reverse engineer all of the various, non-standardized file formats that DigiFX used when making the game, which will be essential for porting the game in the future.</para>

<para>So far, I&apos;ve already been able to reverse engineer the <computeroutput>*.BM</computeroutput> files, which are used for all the static backgrounds in the games, for character portraits, the map, and more. Unfortunately, I likely can&apos;t to share these files, at least not in bulk (see below). I will, however, be sharing a small handful of these images as I show this project off online and I&apos;ll make sure to add a link here in the future if you wish to view those!</para>
</section>
<section xml:id="_index_1autotoc_md2">
<title>Installation</title><section xml:id="_index_1autotoc_md3">
<title>Easiest Way</title>
<para>Navigate to the <link xlink:href="https://github.com/IcePanorama/HarvesterHarvester/releases">releases</link> page and download the latest zip file.</para>

<para>Once downloaded, extract the zip file wherever you&apos;d like and you&apos;re done! See USAGE.md for more details on how to run the program.</para>

<para><emphasis role="bold">NOTE</emphasis>: <emphasis>if you&apos;re reading this in the present, you&apos;ll notice that there currently aren&apos;t any available releases. I&apos;m writing this README in advance &#8211; this project isn&apos;t quite done yet, sorry!</emphasis></para>
</section>
<section xml:id="_index_1autotoc_md4">
<title>Building from source (Linux/MacOS/Unix)</title>
<para>1) Install the following dependencies: <literallayout><computeroutput>gcc&#32;make&#32;mingw32-gcc&#32;clang-tools-extra&#32;valgrind&#32;doxygen
</computeroutput></literallayout> 2) Clone the repo: <literallayout><computeroutput>$&#32;git&#32;clone&#32;https://github.com/IcePanorama/HarvesterHarvester/&#32;&amp;&amp;&#32;cd&#32;HarvesterHarvester
</computeroutput></literallayout> 3) Build using make: <literallayout><computeroutput>$&#32;make&#32;release&#32;#&#32;for&#32;*nix,&#32;x86_64,&#32;and&#32;i686&#32;executables
#&#32;...&#32;or,&#32;alternatively&#32;...
$&#32;make&#32;full&#32;&#32;&#32;&#32;#&#32;for&#32;just&#32;the&#32;*nix&#32;executable
</computeroutput></literallayout> Running <computeroutput>make release</computeroutput> is strongly recommended as the build process for the release target makes use of every single dependency listed above, thus ensuring that you have all the correct packages installed on your machine.</para>

<para>Congrats! You&apos;re now all set to use the program or start contributing.</para>
</section>
</section>
<section xml:id="_index_1autotoc_md5">
<title>A note on piracy</title>
<para>This program requires that you legally own a copy of <emphasis>Harvester</emphasis> in order to source the necessary dat files.</para>

<para>The GOG version (which this project was built around) <link xlink:href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/harvester">is available here for $5.99</link>, although it&apos;s worth noting that it does go on sale rather often.</para>

<para><link xlink:href="https://isthereanydeal.com/game/harvester/info/">Alternatively, visit any of the retailers on this link if you&apos;d rather shop elsewhere</link>.</para>

<para>This project in no way intends to encourage the piracy of DigiFX&apos; software. </para>
</section>
</chapter>
